# Barry Wang, PMP, Prince2, MSP, ITIL, CSM

# Senior Project Manager

Certified Senior Project Manager with over 10 years of experience in cloud, telecom, consulting and system integration, software development in small to large, complex environment. Managing multi-projects with sound business analysis skill and diverse technological background. Leader, mentor and team player interfacing with all levels of management and stakeholders.

Phone: +8613811097069 Email: barrywanghd@163.com

#### **EXPERTISE**

- ➤ Planning and Management: Accountable for creating proposal, defining delivery strategy, getting budget approved, securing contract, engaging key stakeholders, controlling delivery according to baselines and change processes etc. Helped account teams to achieve business targets in 5 extremely tough projects regarding time, budget, solution and resources.
- ➤ Handling Multi Projects: Successfully managed over 18 projects/programs in the past 8 years, including telecom network, IT infrastructure, consulting & system integration, development and subcontract of middle to large scale, diverse solution areas and multi provinces/countries. Project budget ranged to over 10M USD.
- ➤ Team building/Leadership: Drove both psychical and distributed virtual team acting as the bridge of backend (product, logistics, support etc.) and frontend (delivery, operation, sales, customer etc.). Combined both project goal and personal development of team members to reach win-win situation. Led project team of 40+ members including subproject managers.
- ➤ Continues improvement: Innovatively introduced agile methodology to service delivery resulting in 10% efficiency improved considering man effort involved. Kept coaching team's mind set of quality and used bottom-up approach turning around a vital project at risk.
- ➤ **Knowledge Sharing**: Used SharePoint to manage projects, facilitate team collaboration, information and knowledge sharing. Created reused SharePoint web template for large scale projects. Presented project experience in Ericsson global seminars.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS / INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE

- > PMP, Prince2, MSP and Props methodologies, ITIL, SDLC, Agile, MS Office Suite, SharePoint
- BSS,OSS, Media & Application, Cloud, Database, TCP/IP

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- PMP Project Management Professional
- Prince2 (Practitioner) Projects in a Controlled Environment
- ➤ MSP (Practitioner) –Managing Successful Programmes
- ITIL Foundation Certified Version 3
- CSM Certified Scrum Master

Barry Wang Page 1 of 4

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

## Technical Program Manager Amazon Web Service 2015 to Present

- ➤ Develop and manage business-impacting projects that enhance Amazon.com's infrastructure and its operations. Timely execution with the highest degrees of security, performance, availability, and reliability.
- Act as a bridge between infrastructure teams on the ground and business teams to ensure that our stringent standards are met in the most cost-efficient way possible.
- ➤ Drive significant initiatives to drive operational effectiveness and improve our customers' experience while maintaining their privacy. Look for areas where we can gain efficiencies, compress project delivery and reduce costs

### Senior Project Manager Ericsson Region North East Asia 2007 to Present

- ➤ Drove tender, customer negotiation and execution of large-scale, multiple technology projects across region ensuring the successful E2E delivery.
- ➤ Conducted project planning, scoping, budgeting, managing risks, change control, problem solving, quality improvement, communication, handover, subcontractor management etc.
- ➤ Coordinated cross-project activities with commercial, sales, global product unit, local development team, site delivery team and support groups. Built up competence of engineer, solution architecture and project managers with resource owners.

#### Projects & Achievements

- ➤ China Mobile Research Institute NFV virtualized IMS (IAAS) Project. Directed the efforts of sub-project managers, system architects, developers, and system integrators to pass trial test with limited global support. Kept Ericsson in the engagement of China Mobile telecom cloud transformation with positive feedback from customer. Built up local resources' competence by leveraging the possible channels and team self-learning.
- ➤ Hong Kong SmarTone Volte (Voice over LTE i.e. 4G) Project. Served as program director to negotiate scope, beat competitors, secure contract finally. Led a cross-functional team of over 40 members to realize and deploy this complex solution integrating with 2G/3G/4G. Ericsson first commercial launched Volte in this region. Achieved 15% margin improved, shared as best practice and contributed to Ericsson's Volte blueprint. Developed AP/GW solution (AIS, Linux, Oracle, MySQL, C/C++, JAVA, Tomcat, struts2, Mina) which have been reused by 4 different markets. Helped SmarTone become one of the first authorized Iphone6 operators around the world.
- ➤ Hong Kong SmarTone MPBN/PRAN QoS (Quality of Services) Project. Managed design and implementation of E2E QoS for live IP infrastructure (switches, routers, firewalls) and Core/RAN nodes of 2G/3G. Performed QoS audit to align the policy end to end.
- ➤ China Unicom IMS (IP Multimedia System) performance test. Took project manager and overall solution architect role to work out solution, setup e2e system of high dimension, pass all tests within 3 months and secure last ticket for central purchase. Managed 3 vendors (Empirix, Genband and Iskratel) including SOW, commerce, integration and delivery.
- > China Mobile Heilongjiang IMS upgrade. Upgraded the whole IMS and application due to life cycle management. Coached and mentored another experienced project manager from

Barry Wang Page 2 of 4

- planning, resourcing, costing, delivering and handover to the operation team afterward.
- ➤ China Mobile MBC (Mobile Broadband Charging) Consulting Project. Took project manager and business analysis role providing technology consulting about mobile broadband charging for coming 4G services. Provided PoC based on 3PP BCS (Telcordia Broadband Charging System) solution in live network. Agile development for the special requirements.
- ➤ Japan SoftBank OSS(Operation Support System) ENIC development. Led team to enhance the data analysis function of the current OSS system, develop separate requirements for KPI analysis and distribution. Secured another 2 Purchase Orders for new requirements.
- ➤ China Mobile e-Channel Consulting project. Took project manager and business analysis role to re-engineer business process of customer's e-channel to address the increasing requirements of online business. Defined technical specification to improve the current CRM (Customer Relationship Management) system regarding product management, payment etc. Secured successive contract to develop and deliver the online payment gateway.
- ➤ Hong Kong SmarTone Proof of Concept for Charging System. Demonstrated and convinced rigorous SmarTone of system's flexibility and functionality by leveraging local development competence in an E2E (End to End) POC based on Ericsson Charging System within a tight schedule.
- ➤ China Mobile Awareness of Charging. Led customer engagement by initiating a small field trial convincing customer the benefit of real time notification. Then turned into commercial contract as online charging gateway serving 22.8M subscribers in HLJ and 6.8M subscriber in LN. Developed online charging gateway (Linux, MySQL, C/C++, JAVA, Tomcat, struts2, Mina).
- ➤ China Mobile IMS (IP Multimedia Subsystem) Project. Took the total PM role to deliver this first IMS commercial project in HLJ province of China Mobile. The project covered 13 cities and IOT with 21 provinces.
- ➤ China Mobile Web Gateway Project. Managed the lab testing and commercial site deployment to setup dedicated web gateway to address the increasing data service of 3G.
- ➤ China Mobile (M2M) Machine to Machine for 2 provinces. Managed partner to deliver first 2 commercial M2M contracts providing the platform for potential industries. Led partner and customer to analyse business requirements, find industry application, and define business cases.
- ➤ China Unicom 2G/3G device Management for 11 provinces. Leveraged customer requirement and Ericsson experience in device management to work out the local solution. Managed team to develop a new system and deliver the solution in 11 provinces. Outsourced most of the development and delivery tasks to 3PP and took the key role by Ericsson.
- ➤ China Netcom Integrated Service Platform for 4 provinces. Transformed part of business support system from traditional vertical architecture to flat one. Provided transitional consulting for the operation. Managed delivery of 4 provinces as the program manager.
- ➤ China Mobile Automatic Device Management for 4 provinces. Investigated business requirements in China market and developed the local solution based on global product. Managed the delivery of first 4 projects in different provinces. This solution was sold to 24 provinces in China Mobile and China Unicom afterwards.

Team Lead, Crossbow Technology Inc. 2006–2007

Barry Wang Page 3 of 4

Drove software development and testing related to hardware platform in machine to machine solution. Coordinated software team and hardware team to provide customer solution.

#### Projects & Achievements

- ➤ Designed architecture of hardware driver, led its development and migrated to new platform. Redesigned the timer component in kernel to enhance performance of sleeping mechanism and scheduling which prolonged the life span of power-efficient sensor node.
- > Drove the project to establish the automatic testing system and implemented this system in manufacturer which improved the product lead time around 10%.
- Investigated and designed solution to the Landslide Monitoring Project for Hong Kong government and Security Monitoring System of coal mine for China Coal Research Institute which was technically advanced in the ad-hoc mesh network and power consumption.

# Technical Project Manager, Lucent Technology Inc. 1998–2001

- > Started as an engineer deploying 5ESS system and achieved good technical reputation very soon, then supported key projects on troubleshooting and training sub-contractors.
- ➤ Drove rollout of large scale telecom network system of 5ESS, PHS etc. involving planning, logistics, installation (engineering, power, cabling, networking, transmission, integration, tuning, end to end testing, dry run etc.), acceptance and handover etc.

# Projects & Achievements

- ➤ China Netcom Personal Handy System. Managed rollout of Personal Handy System in 3 big cities of GanSu province of over 4000 base stations, ~100 switching sites/data centres, led a team of over 70+ combined from Lucent and Sub Contractors. Jointly launched the system with customer and established good relationship.
- ➤ One Tel MSC in Perth Australia. Led a small team of 5 engineers successfully installing a medium sized MSC with high quality within one month in Perth, Australia. Earned the credibility and opened the cooperation between Lucent Australia and Lucent Tsing Dao.
- ➤ China Netcom MSC migration. Set up a new medium sized MSC and migrated half of the subscribers from current MSC to the newly built one smoothly without any traffic impact.

#### **Awards**

- Excellent Employee of Ericsson in 2009, 2012 and 2014
- ➤ Excellent Team Award CNC Integrated Service Platform 1.0 Phase 2 Rollout in 2008
- Excellent Employee of Lucent Tsing Dao in 1999 and 2000

# Trainings

- ➤ Leadership for Professionals / Leadership for Project Managers
- > SI Campus/Enjoy Customer Service

Barry Wang Page 4 of 4

> Way to Ericsson Agile leader/ Way to Ericsson Coacher/ Kan Ban/This is Lean

### **Education**

- 2003–2006 Institute of Software, Chinese Academy of Science Master in Computer Networks and Multimedia Communication
- > 1994–1998 Ocean University of China Bachelor of Computer Software (Minored in Law)

Barry Wang Page 5 of 4